{
    "id": "c347027cc3604d588742fd6b75e51ead",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My brother ………………………….. to be an actor.",
            "description": "Use the simple present tense to talk about needs, wants, aspirations etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "aspires",
                "is aspiring",
                "aspire"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e5e72cd968264bea8aa1a5bb4ea68896"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. to talk to her ever again.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "don't want",
                "am not wanting",
                "have not wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d3cc7e5ee1224f20ab48cf76f8941a3e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked him why he ……………………….. upset.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3690886927b14d3f9392b4f73f4a7e83"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wondered where she ……………………………",
            "description": "'Where has she disappeared?' I wondered. Present perfect in the direct speech becomes past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "disappeared",
                "has disappeared",
                "had disappeared"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "74a2c967419944a6924bc51d7b213528"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if I ……………………. help her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "53e42ead8ca54677bb87c81502921b6d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will tell you as soon as I …………………………. from them.",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, use a simple present in the subordinate clause to refer to future. ",
            "answers": [
                "hear",
                "will hear",
                "heard"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "907d5587db6f4ed2b052c85b8d9839b3"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………. really hard.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "works",
                "work"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "159b23ed95dd4af7b55890f92f0374f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Meat …………………………. with me.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "does not agree",
                "is not agreeing",
                "hasn't agreed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "feb4f6fe7c334fcb8b8b19493de1fb8e"
        },
        {
            "question": "He never ………………………… to me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is listening",
                "listens",
                "has listened"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "085dc8d3802e453798697354455f4f57"
        },
        {
            "question": "Birds of a feather ……………………….. together.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are flocking",
                "flock",
                "flocking"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a668462558944d259c25a161605a8ec7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. on this project for six months.",
            "description": "Use the present perfect continuous to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "am working",
                "have been working",
                "work"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0f8ef1d1df8a4ff6ad7efcd191a86029"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who ……………………….. the light bulb?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "invented",
                "has invented",
                "did invent"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7732bea64f4b41488cb787a5c4b0169e"
        }
    ]
}